Guide to the Neill Family papers 1886-1964
Montana Historical Society
- George G.e. Neill
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include G.C. Elliott; Bob Veitch; John M. Evans; Beaverhead National Forest; B.L. Forsyth; S.V. Stewart; C.E. Brown; C.N. Newhall; Millard C. Evenson; Mrs. Ben Adams; Arthur L. Sheppard; Vosburg Mining Company; United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Company; Sullivan Mining Company; Newark Trust Company), 1934 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include G.C. Elliott; Bob Veitch; Beaverhead National Forest; Arthur L. Sheppard; United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Company; Sullivan Mining Company; Miss E.E. Holcomb; E.A. Rowe; Jess E. Pierman; E.T. Dusenbury re Harral Tenney; C.F. Guerin; Oscar Weber; R.F. Scott; Margaret G. Neill; Martha Daly), 1935 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include G.C. Elliott; Bob Veitch; Philip G. Cole; Beaverhead National Forest; R.F. Scott; Will A. Campbell; Charles F. Guerin; Monarch Lumber Company; Lena Evans; Burton K. Wheeler), 1936 (Box-folder 8 / 7)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include G.C. Elliott; Bob Veitch; W. Elmer Holt; Beaverhead National Forest; C.E. Brown; James K. Sloan; Charles W. English; R.F. Scott; W.E. Cullen; W.M. "Mudge" Brooks; Paul M. Hale; Jess E. Pierman; John H. Crone; Frank N. Crone; Philip G. Cole; Julia A. Bennett; George J. Willock; Hjalmar Engstrom), 1937 (Box-folder 8 / 8)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include G.C. Elliott; Bob Veitch; Philip G. Cole; R.F. Scott; United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Company; Alvin C. Rowe; Collins Land Company; Beaverhead National Forest; John H. Crone; Frank N. Crone; William S. Stone; James E. Murray; Edward D. Neill; Alfred Halderson; Hjalmar Emgstrom), 1938 (Box-folder 8 / 9)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include R.H. Fletcher; Burton K. Wheeler; William S. Stone; Mary Gordon McKinnon, Quincy Hotel; Bob Vaitch; P.B. Snelson; John H. Crone; Jess E. Pierman; R.F. Scott; Alvin Rowe; James E. Murray), 1939 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include R.H. Fletcher; Philip G. Cole; William S. Stone; Mary Gordon McKinnon, Quincy Hotel; Alfred Halderson; John W. "Jack" Power; Bob Veitch; Beaverhead National Forest; M.E. Chaffee; John H. Crone), 1940 (Box-folder 8 / 11)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include M.E. Chaffee; Frank N. Crone; Mary Gordon McKinnon, Quincy Hotel; Alfred Halderson; Barnes-King Development Company; Bob Veitch; Beaverhead National Forest; M.E. Chaffee; John H. Crone; William S. Stone; H.W. Carver; R.H. Fletcher), 1941 (Box-folder 8 / 12)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include William S. Stone; G.H. Randall; Alfred Halderson; Bob Veitch; H.W. Carver; U.S. War Production Board; Edward D. Neill; G.C. Elliott; Mary Gordon McKinnon, Quincy Hotel; Beaverhead National Forest; United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Company; Montana Club), 1942 (Box-folder 9 / 1)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Edward D. Neill re his mother Anna B. Neill; William S. Stone; Bob Veitch; Mary Gordon McKinnon, Quincy Hotel; Alfred Halderson; Sullivan Valve and Engineering Company), 1943 (Box-folder 9 / 2)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Edward D. Neill re his mother Anna B. Neill; William S. Stone; Bob Veitch; Mary Gordon McKinnon, Quincy Hotel; Alfred Halderson; United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Company; H.W. Carver, East Pacific Mine; Bertrand L. Ball; Collins Land Company), 1944 (Box-folder 9 / 3)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Company; Alvin C. Rowe; Frank N. Crone; John H. Crone; Joe T. France; Alex Stuart; C.B. Power; T.B. Weir; Alfred Halderson), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 9 / 4)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Jess Pierman; Lena Evans; Beaverhead National Forest; W.E. Cullen; Edward D. Neill; William S. Stone; R.H. Fletcher; Mike Mansfield; T.V. Bunner), 1947-1949 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Beaverhead National Forest; Mike Mansfield; T.V. Bunner; Collins Land Company; MacAlester College re Edward Duffield Neill Room in Library; Collins Land Company; Russel Liston; John W. Schroeder; George J. Willock; Joe T. France), 1950-1952 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include R.H. Fletcher; Marylou Bowman; Beaverhead National Forest; Joe T. France; Collins Land Company; John W. Schroeder; W. Bert Fields; Montana Club; Anne B. Sibley), 1953-1960, undated (Box-folder 9 / 7)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1912-1925 (Box-folder 9 / 8-15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1944 (Box-folder 10 / 1-14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1960, undated (Box-folder 11 / 1-4)
    - Letters of endorsement of George Neill as Receiver of Helena Land Office, 1914, 1920 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
    - Letters of endorsement of George Neill as Helena Postmaster, 1933 (Box-folder 11 / 6-7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (includes W.R. Church to Philip G. Cole; Ben R. Roberts to A.H. Graham; A.A. Shields to R.H. Fletcher), 1911-1952, undated (Box-folder 11 / 8)
  - Court Papers
    - Miscellaneous (includes Grace Mitchell et al. vs. The Banking Corporation of Montana, et al.; General Surety Company bankruptcy; Mark A. Haynes vs. George G.E. Neill, et al.; Barnett Iron and Machinery Company reorganization), 1919-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 9)
  - Financial Records
    - Assay reports, 1937 (Box-folder 11 / 10)
    - Invoices: Montana Club, 1908-1927, 1952 (Box-folder 11 / 11)
    - Invoices: plumbing (mostly Quincy Hotel), 1921-1935 (Box-folder 11 / 12)
    - Invoices: miscellaneous, 1906-1953 (Box-folder 11 / 13-14)
    - Newark Trust and Safe Deposit Company loan, 1913-1945 (Box-folder 11 / 15)
    - Taxes: Douglas County, Wisconsin, property, 1913-1924 (Box-folder 11 / 16)
    - Travel voucher for work for Federal Housing Authority, 1934 (Box-folder 11 / 17)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes bonds, leases, agreements, options, Quincy Hotel bills of sale), 1913-1940 (Box-folder 11 / 18)
  - Subject Files
    - Barnes-King Development Company, 1908-1922 (Box-folder 11 / 19)
    - State Fairgrounds, 1909-1914, undated (Box-folder 11 / 20)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Plans and drawings (includes plans for office building for R.H. Fletcher, George C. Elliott's hotel at Wade Lake, plans for George Neill's cabin at Cliff Lake) [Oversize Box], 1929, 1931, undated (Oversizebox 16)
    - Miscellaneous (includes stock ownership, list of patented mining claims in Helena Mining District, poem "Willie", list of property ownership in vicinity of Holter Dam site), 1914-1945, undated (Box-folder 11 / 21)
  - Clippings
    - Gallatin County Development Association; Democratic politics, 1928, 1933 (Box-folder 11 / 22)
- Elisha S. Clark
  - Financial Records
    - Invoices (includes his estate), 1887-1896 (Box-folder 11 / 23)
- George Evans
  - Legal Documents
    - Harriet B. Miles Estate, 1888-1892 (Box-folder 11 / 24)
- Independent Investment Company
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include U.S. Treasury Dept., J.W. Power), 1914, 1918 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes tax receipts, invoices, promissory notes, receipts), 1904-1928 (Box-folder 12 / 2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstracts of title for Independent Building, 1904-1928 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
    - Miscellaneous (includes deeds, agreements, applications for city loans, mortgages), 1906-1925 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation, 1906 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
    - Minute book, 1906-1916 (Box-folder 12 / 6)
    - Stock certificates, 1906-1918 (Box-folder 12 / 7)
- Independent Publishing Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include A.H. Wethey; R.F. Scott; J. Henry Longmaid; Great Northern Railway Company; H.J. Kelly; Lewis Penwell; Adams Heating-Plumbing Company; Montana State Boiler Inspector; T.J. Walsh; J.S. Kirtley), 1904-1926, undated (Box-folder 12 / 8)
  - Court Papers
    - Fred Whiteside vs. Independent Publishing Company, et al. complaint, 1899 (Box-folder 12 / 9)
  - Financial Records
    - Inventories, 1910-1911, undated (Box-folder 12 / 10)
    - Invoices, 1918-1934 (Box-folder 12 / 11)
    - Plumbing bills, 1914, 1921-1934 (Box-folder 12 / 12)
    - Miscellaneous (includes claims for "special arrangements" for newspapers, taxes, promissory notes), 1906-1915, undated (Box-folder 12 / 13)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes agreements, leases, mortgage), 1901-1917 (Box-folder 12 / 14)
  - Subject Files
    - Electric motor, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 12 / 15)
    - State printing contract (includes legislation, contracts, disputes with other printers, etc.), 1892-1907 (Box-folder 12 / 16-17)
  - Miscellany
    - Architectural drawings by Cass Gilbert for additions to Independent Building [Overisze Box], undated (Oversizebox 16)
    - Boiler inspection certificates, list of stockholders, mailing list, 1913-1926, undated (Box-folder 12 / 18)
    - "Specifications for telephone directories to be furnished Rocky Mountain Bell Telephone Company", undated (Box-folder 12 / 19)
- Lewis And Clarke Democratic County Central Committee
  - Miscellany
    - Poll books (lists registered Democrats in each ward of Helena and in each community in the county), circa 1900 (Volume 5-6)
- Madison River Improvement Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Jeremiah Collins; U.S. Treasury Dept.; Madison County Treasurer; Madison County Clerk and Recorder; U.S. General Land Office; Mabel Deering; Montana Power Company; James T. Fisher; O.A. Fallang; H.L. Kohler, Three Forks Commercial Club; James E. Murray; U.S. Bureau of Reclamation), 1910, 1921-1938, 1950 (Box-folder 13 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Taxes, 1919-1937 (Box-folder 13 / 2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deed from Reynolds Prosser for land along Madison River, 1920 (Box-folder 13 / 3)
  - Miscellany
    - Sketch maps, assay reports, lists of land, 1909-1937, undated (Box-folder 13 / 4)
- Montana Outdoor Advertising Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include General Outdoor Advertising Company; Packer Advertising Corporation; Batten, Barton, Durstine and Osborn, Inc.; Outdoor Advertising Association of America; Edith Black Lemmon; Helena Development Company; Federal Housing Administration), 1927-1937 (Box-folder 13 / 5)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Western Air Express Corporation; Edith Black Lemmon; Thomas Cruse Mining and Development Company; Lester Loble; Tiffin Art Metal Company; Standard Sales Service Bulletin; R.H. Fletcher), 1938-1956 (Box-folder 13 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include R.H. Fletcher; Robert A. Poore), 1957-1961 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial summary and real estate sales, 1952-1958 (Box-folder 13 / 8)
  - Miscellany
    - List of sign locations; charter for Outdoor Advertising Association of Montana, 1929, 1957 (Box-folder 13 / 9)
- Montana Properties Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include William Scallon; U.S. Treasury Dept.; Edmond G. Toomey), 1917-1947 (Box-folder 13 / 10)
  - Court Papers
    - City of Helena vs. Montana Properties Company, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 13 / 11)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deeds, 1921, 1925 (Box-folder 13 / 12)
- Montana Rapid Transit Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include William A. Clark; W.H. Gerry, Jr.; Helena Commercial Club; Northern Pacific Railway Company; Collins Land Company; U.S. Secretary of Interior; J.C. Thompson; W.R. Allen; F.W. Bibb; A.B. Leach and Company; Butte Electric Railway Company; Marcus L. Hewett; J.C. Pyle; Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company; Alhambra Hot Springs Hotel), 1908-1909 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include J.W. McFarland; Great Northern Railway Company; Marcus L. Hewett; Conrad-Stanford Company; A.B. Leach and Company; W.H. Gerry, Jr.; A.J. Earling, Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company; A.W. Verharen; A.C. Pratt; E.C. Day; J.G. White and Company; Paul T. Brady; Samuel MacLean; J. Miller Smith), 1910-1911, 1916, 1921, 1923, 1927 (Box-folder 14 / 2)
  - Employment Records
    - Payroll [ Oversize Box], 1909 (Oversizebox 16)
  - Financial Records
    - Bank book and deposit slips, 1912-1922 (Box-folder 14 / 3)
    - Cancelled checks: money advanced to company by Neill and Gerry, 1909-1915 (Box-folder 14 / 4)
    - Checkstubs, 1909-1922 (Box-folder 14 / 5)
    - Financial summaries, 1910, undated (Box-folder 14 / 6)
    - Insurance, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 14 / 7)
    - Ledger, 1909-1922 (Volume 7)
    - Report on ticket sales at Jefferson City, Corbin, Clancy, Alhambra, etc. [Great Northern Railway Company?], 1910-1911 (Volume 8)
    - Taxes, 1909, 1922 (Box-folder 14 / 9)
    - Transcript of books, 1909-1913 (Box-folder 14 / 10)
    - Trial balances, 1909-1921 (Box-folder 14 / 11)
    - U.S. capital stock tax returns, 1917-1925 (Box-folder 14 / 12)
    - U.S. and Montana corporate tax returns [Oversize Box], 1909-1922 (Oversizebox 16)
    - Vouchers, 1912-1918 (Box-folder 14 / 13-14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1909-1922 (Box-folder 14 / 15)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes deeds, rights-of-way, agreements, etc.), 1908-1914, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 14 / 16-17)
  - Organization
    - Annual statements of corporation, 1910-1922 (Box-folder 15 / 1)
    - Certificate of increase in stock, certificate of change of location, dissolution, etc., 1909-1910, 1925 (Box-folder 15 / 2)
    - Record books (includes minutes, articles of incorporation, bylaws, legal documents, etc.), 1909-1924 (Box-folder 15 / 3-4)
    - Stock and bond certificates, 1909-1924 (Box-folder 15 / 5)
    - Subscription certificates, 1909 (Box-folder 15 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous (includes proxies, meeting notices, lists of stockholders, etc.), 1909-1924 (Box-folder 15 / 7-8)
  - Printed Material
    - "Montana Rapid Transit Company: Helena and Butte Interurban", circa 1909 (Box-folder 15 / 9)
  - Miscellany
    - Lists of properties acquired by company, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 15 / 10)
    - Plans and drawings: route of Montana Rapid Transit Company tracks through Helena and East Helena [Oversize: See Archives Map Case], undated (Oversize-folder 1)
- Transfers To Other Programs
  - Transfers
    - Lists of maps and photographs transferred to Library Map Collection and Photograph Archives respectively (Box-folder 15 / 11)